Guide to the Hisham Khatib Collection of photographic prints AD.MC.030
Akkasah: Photography Archive (NYU Abu Dhabi)
- Postcards, 731 (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
  - A hand-colored postcard of the road to the Pyramids in Cairo, Circa 1899-1908; ref619; The Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo (Egypt); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Cairo, Egypt; Landscapes; English Writing; Rivers; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Pyramids
  - A hand-colored postcard of the statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps (Statue de Ferdinand de Lesseps) (no. 337), Circa 1890-1940; ref620; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Seas; Port Said, Egypt; Mediterranean Sea; Monuments/Memorials; Statues/Sculptures; French Writing; Buildings; Water; Lesseps, Ferdinand de (Marie, Comte), 1805-1894
  - A postcard of "Banks of the Nile" a painting by Ella Du Cane (Series no. 10), Circa 1913-1935; ref621; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Paintings; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Palm Trees; Nile River; Rivers; Water; English Writing; Architecture; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A postcard of the interior of the Mosque of Mohamed Ali at the Citadel in Cairo, Circa 1890-1940; ref622; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Cairo, Egypt; Mosque of Muhammad Ali Pasha; Mosques; Religious Sites; Architecture; Buildings; Citadel, Cairo, Egypt; English Writing
  - A postcard of two lion statues on the Kasr-el-Nil Bridge in Cairo, Circa 1890-1940; ref623; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Statues/Sculptures; Animals; Carriages/Coaches; Transportation; Horses; Bridges; Street Lamps; Buildings; Architecture; Men; Regional/National Dress; English Writing; Cairo, Egypt; Horses; Prams/Buggies/Strollers; Women; Hats; Palm Trees; Streets/Roads
  - A hand-colored postcard of an illustration of the Pyramids of Gizeh (Les pyramides de Gizeh)., Circa 1890-1940; ref624; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Pyramids; Architecture; Buildings; Palm Trees; Nile River; Rivers; Water; Camels; Animals; Men; Regional/National Dress; Giza, Egypt; French Writing; English Writing; German Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A hand-colored postcard of the Works of the Suez Canal Company at Port Said (Ateliers de la cie du Canal de Suez, Circa 1890-1940; ref625; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Buildings; Architecture; Streets/Roads; Port Said, Egypt; French Writing; English Writing; Landscapes; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A postcard of two people near the Pyramids during flood time, Circa 1904-1939; ref626; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Architecture; Buildings; Palm Trees; Men; Regional/National Dress; Nile River; Rivers; Water; English Writing; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A postcard of the Pyramids and the Village during Nile Flood, Circa 1904-1939; ref627; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Buildings; Architecture; Nile River; Rivers; Water; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; English Writing
  - A postcard of a man on a camel in front of the Pyramid of Khafre (no. 171), Circa 1904-1939; ref628; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Palm Trees; Pyramids; Giza, Egypt; Architecture; English Writing; Camels; Animals; Men; Regional/National Dress; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A postcard of a man on a camel near The Great Sphinx and the Pyramids in Giza, Circa 1904-1939; ref629; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Pyramids; The Great Sphinx of Giza; Giza, Egypt; Architecture; English Writing; Animals; Camels; Men; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts
  - A hand-colored postcard of merchants in Cairo (Le Caire Marchands des arbres)., Circa 1899-1908; ref630; The Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo (Egypt); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Cairo, Egypt; Animals; Camels; Carriages/Coaches; Buildings; Men; Turbans; Regional/National Dress; Regional/National Dress; French Writing; English Writing; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Facial Hair; Group Portraits
  - A postcard of the limestone statue of King Zoser (no. 700), Circa 1904-1939; ref631; Lehnert & Landrock; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Statues/Sculptures; Archaeological Sites/Artifacts; Egypt
  - A hand-colored postcard of the offices of the Suez Canal Company at Port Said (Bureaux de la cie du Canal de Suez), Circa 1890-1940; ref632; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Buildings; Architecture; French Writing; English Writing; Port Said, Egypt; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Mediterranean Sea; Seas; Water; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A hand-colored postcard of people sitting on the banks of the Suez Canal (Navire dans le Canal), Circa 1890-1940; ref633; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Seas; Water; Boats/Ships; Port Said, Egypt; Transportation; Mediterranean Sea; Men; Regional/National Dress; French Writing; English Writing; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Landscapes
  - A hand-colored postcard of the Mahmoudieh Canal in Alexandria, Circa 1890-1940; ref634; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Alexandria, Egypt; Canals; Water; Animals; Men; English Writing; Landscapes
  - A hand-colored postcard of a general view of Alexandria., Circa 1890-1940; ref635; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Alexandria, Egypt; Buildings; Seas; Boats/Ships; Transportation; Water; English Writing; Landscapes; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A hand-colored postcard of an illustration of Cherif Pacha street in Alexandria, Circa 1890-1940; ref636; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Alexandria, Egypt; Buildings; Individual Portraits; Shops; Streets/Roads; Street Lamps; Men; Carriages/Coaches; Horses; Architecture; English Writing; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A hand-colored postcard of the procession of the Mahmal (Holy Carpet) in Alexandria., Circa 1890-1926; ref637; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Alexandria, Egypt; Crowds; Parades/Processions; Buildings; Architecture; Religious Ceremony; English Writing; Men; Group Portraits; Carpets/Rugs; Streets/Roads
  - A hand-colored postcard of the Statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps at Port Said (no. 777), Circa 1899-1908; ref638; The Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo (Egypt); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Port Said, Egypt; Monuments/Memorials; Statues/Sculptures; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; French Writing; Boats/Ships; Transportation; English Writing; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Lesseps, Ferdinand de (Marie, Comte), 1805-1894
  - A hand-colored postcard of a painting of a domed building next to a stream in a village, Circa 1899-1908; ref639; The Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo (Egypt); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Buildings; Architecture; Egypt; Palm Trees; Rivers; Water; Men; Women; Regional/National Dress; French Writing; Paintings; Landscapes; Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting
  - A postcard of a road next to the Suez Canal, Circa 1930-1950; ref640; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Streets/Roads; Cars/Trucks; Seas; Boats/Ships; English Writing; Transportation; Suez, Egypt; Landscapes
  - A postcard of a birds-eye view of Port Said, Circa 1890-1940; ref641; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; English Writing; Buildings; Port Said, Egypt; French Writing; Landscapes
  - A hand-colored postcard of the Delta Barrage, Circa 1899-1908; ref642; The Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo (Egypt); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Hand-colored Photographs/Hand-tinting; Postcards; Bridges; Architecture; Dams/Barrages; Cairo, Egypt; Nile River; Rivers; English Writing; Water
  - A postcard of the statue of Ferdinand de Lesseps at Port Said, Circa 1899-1940; ref643; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Statues/Sculptures; Monuments/Memorials; Port Said, Egypt; French Writing; English Writing; Lesseps, Ferdinand de (Marie, Comte), 1805-1894
  - A postcard of boats in the west bay in Alexandria (no.5)., Circa 1890-1940; ref644; Lévy Fils et cie, Paris-Versailles (France) (Active circa 1872–1900); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Alexandria, Egypt; Boats/Ships; Men; Transportation; Mediterranean Sea; Seas; Water; Buildings; English Writing; French Writing
  - A postcard of the port with boats and the Suez Canal offices at Port Said (Le Port)., July 1915; ref645; The Cairo Postcard Trust, Cairo (Egypt); 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Port Said, Egypt; Seas; Mediterranean Sea; Water; Boats/Ships; Transportation; French Writing; English Writing; Buildings; Architecture
  - A postcard of a general view of the City of the Dead in Cairo., unknown; ref646; 1 Photographic Prints (Object Digital copy only 030_ref517-ref715)
    Postcards; Buildings; Architecture; French Writing; English Writing; Cairo, Egypt